LEIGH B. BIENEN PAPERS (APAP312) 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- New Jersey Proportionality Review Project Records, 1908, 1973-1996, Undated; 1; 6.8
  - Notes, 1991 October 7; Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1991 October 24; 1992 February 20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. McDougald (mental illness), 1991 October 31 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Data Tables and Notes, 1991 November 15; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Appendix to Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant volume III (Piece F), 1991 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Table 5: Table of Ptrail by County, 1991 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Strong Republican trend registered by state's voters", 1991 November 19 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief and Appendix on behalf of the State of New Jersey Addressing Proportionality Review, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant Volume II (Piece D), 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey an Independent Analysis of Data on Capital Charging and Sentencing", 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey an Independent Analysis of Data on Capital Charging and Sentencing", 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality Review of Death Sentences in New Jersey", 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Weisberg Report Memorandum, 1991 November 26 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Judith L. Borman, Bernadette DcCastro, Dale Jones, memorandum and discussing Weisberg Report, 1991 December 20 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Reply Brief of Amicus Curiae, 1991 December 30 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Draft of letter from Leigh Bienen concerning New Jersey v. Marshall and 1992 Proportionality review legislation, ca. 1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey v. Marko Bey, 1992 January 13; 1993 February 11 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Review Articles, 1992 January 21 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Weisberg Response with notes, 1992 January 29 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - New Jersey Assembly Bills, 1992 March 17 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Testimony of Alexander H. Southwell before the Senate Judiciary Committee of the New Jersey Legislature concerning Proportionality Review, 1992 March 23 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Revised Data Collection Instrument (DCI), 1992 April 21 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 25th and 26th wave - list of cases with project status clearly out, 1992 April 22 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - David C. Baldus, "The Proportionality Review of Death Sentences: New Jersey Options", 1992 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1992 April 30; 1992 December 3 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - New Case Summaries - No Penalty Trial Cases, 1992 June; 1992 September (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - New Jersey v. Kevin Jackson, 1992 June 10 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall - Notice of Motion for Reconsideration of Proportionality Review, 1992 August 6 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1992 August 17 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - New Jersey Public Defenders - cost and budget, 1992 August 24 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Boxes stored for Leigh Bienen, 1992 August 28 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Constitutional Amendment to Require State Funding of the Judicial System, 1992 October 21 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Claudia Van Wyt and DCI, 1992 November 12 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - transcript of A.O.C Meeting, 1992 November 13 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Data Tables, 1992 December 2 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Proportionality Review, 1992 December 9; 1993 February 18 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - New Jersey v. Martini - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Tables of Cases and Summaries, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principal Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 January 28 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principal Appendix to Brief Volume II, 1993 January 28 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Technical Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 January 28 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Technical Appendix to Brief Volume II, 1993 January 28 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. Bey - Appendices and Tables, 1993 January 28 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendices and Tables [1 of 2], 1993 January 28 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendices and Tables [2 of 2], 1993 January 28 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - DCI Data on "Afterthought" Robbery/Murder cases, 1993 February 13 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief on behalf of Defendant - Appellant, ca. 1993 March (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Principle Appendix on brief on Behalf of Appellant - Defendant Volume I, ca. 1993 March (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendix to Brief Volume I, 1993 March 23 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Status of New Jersey Capital Cases, 1993 March 30 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini -Proportionality Review, 1993 April 27 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief on behalf of the Attorney General Amicus Curiae -, 1993 April 29 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Appendix on behalf of the Attorney General Amicus Curiae -, 1993 April 29 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Reply Brief on Behalf of Defendant - Appellant, 1993 May 6 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey Proportionality Review Data file used in New Jersey v. Martini, 1993 May 18 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini, 1993 June 2; 1993 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - David Baldus and George Woodworth, "Proportionality: the view of the Special Master," and Herbert I. Weisberg, "Proportionality: An Alternative View." (Prepublication), 1993 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993 June 25 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini, 1993 July (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendices and Tables [1 of 2], 1993 July 23 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - Appendices and Tables [2 of 2], 1993 July 23 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey - Brief and Appendix of Amicus Curiae, 1993 September 24 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - New Jersey v. John Martini - On Proportionality Review of a Death Sentence, 1993 September 30 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall reused Appendix to Defendant's Amended Petition for Post-Conviction Relief, 1993 October; 1993 November (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Report of the New Jersey Supreme Court's Ad Hoc Committee on Jury Selection in Criminal Cases, 1993 October (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey Motion to Submit Evidence of Continuing Race Disparities, 1993 October 21 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Relief [1 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Relief [2 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Appendix to Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Review [1 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey v. Robert O. Marshall Appendix to Amended Petition for Post - Conviction Review [2 of 2], 1993 October 22 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Wave 32, Modifications to Data Collection Instrument, 1994 May 13 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994 October 18 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Death Penalty Research - Print out of Capital cases, 1995 July 13 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Memo: Prejudicial Factors Death in Sentencing, 1995 December 20 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey v. Donald Coftin, 1996 November 18 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Public Defender Capital Case Monthly Report, 1996 November 18 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Appendix B, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - David Baldus Survey to Attorneys of Record in Capital Cases, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Data Tables, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Data Tables - Appendix B Tables, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Data Tables - Background Tables, n=146, wh/non-wh, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Data Tables - Background not used, n=146, wh/bc/h, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Data Tables - not used, white/non-white, n=252, Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Data Tables - old regressions not published with RL Ron interim reports, Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Law and Society Paper - tables, not to publish, Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey v. Marko Bey Brief on Behalf of the State of New Jersey, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Capital Cases in other states, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Notes from October 29, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Proportionality Review, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - References, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Stage Jumping Analysis, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Supplement to working Draft of Interim Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court - Appendix E, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Table I (hand written) - Distribution of cases by tear and county, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Table B III - Statutory Mitigating Factors, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Faculty Papers and Scholarly Research Material, 1979-2011, Undated; 2; 7
  This series documents Leigh Bienen's work as a legal scholar of the death penalty and her teaching career at Princeton University and Northwestern University. Included are records from her scholarly research on capital punishment consisting of questionnaires, case summaries, and procedural wirings. This includes the New Jersey Public Defender Homicide Study. The series also contains Bienen's publications on the death penalty, conference materials, syllabi and teaching material, and reports, legislation, and publications used directly in her research.
  - Research on Capital Punishment cost, 1983; 1987; 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Literature on Determinate Sentencing in Illinois with annotations, 1984; 1993; 2004; 2009; 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Homicide Study - Appendix D: Case Summaries [1 of 2], ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Homicide Study - Appendix D: Case Summaries [2 of 2], ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Homicide Study - Coding Interpretations and Instructions, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Homicide Study - Plea/Trial Code, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Homicide Study Master List, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Homicide Study Plea/Trial Code, 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Homicide Study Questionnaire, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Homicide Study Questionnaire, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Homicide Study Questionnaire, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Homicide Study Questionnaire with notes, ca. 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alfonso and Baur Penalty Phase Training Program (New Jersey), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Homicide Study Questionnaire and Forms, 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Leigh B. Bienen and Neil Alan Weiner, "The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Homicide Cases from 1982 - 1986" - Supplement to Preliminary Report, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Capital Jury Project - William Bones Data, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Leigh B. Bienen, et. al., "The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: The role of Prosecutorial Discretion" Rutgers Law Review print copy with notes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Leigh Bienen, et. al., The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Interim Report, Part 1 [1 of 2], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Leigh Bienen, et. al., The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Interim Report, Part 1 [2 of 2], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Leigh Bienen, et. al., The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Interim Report 2 [1 of 3], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Leigh Bienen, et. al., The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Interim Report 2 [2 of 3], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Leigh Bienen, et. al., The Reimposition of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: Interim Report 2 [3 of 3], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Leigh Bienen, "No Savings In Lives or Money With Death Penalty, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Leigh Bienen, "No Savings In Lives or Money With Death Penalty," The New York Times, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Homicide Study - Appendix A,B,C, ca. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Special Commission on the Administration of Justice in Cook County - Final Report, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Civil Liberties Union of New Jersey and Habeas Corpus, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Inventory from Watt Espy, Capital Punishment Research Project, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts, notes, research material and correspondence from "Proportionality Review of Capital Cases by State High Courts: Only 'The Appearance of Justice?' " and New York University Talk, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Capital Jury Project - Natural Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Capital Jury Project - Natural Science Foundation proposal to study Capital sentencing, comments by Leigh Bienen, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Criminologists for Abolition of the Death Penalty, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Missouri Proportionality review case citations, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program - NYU Review of Law and Social Change Colloquium, Challenging the Death Penalty: 1990 and Beyond (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Charles Silagy v. Howard Peters III, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Statement of David C. Baldus before Committee on the Judiciary, United States House of Representatives concerning Arbitrariness and Discrimination in the Imposition of the Death Penalty, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bill Proposing lethal injection, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Capital Jury Project, National Study of Juror Decision Making in Capital Cases, Grant proposal and Survey Sample, ca. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Deputy Attorney General Class visit and death penalty legislative hearing transcript, 1991 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Capital Jury Project - Working Paper 1, Background and Research Design, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cost of Capital Punishment - notes, 1991 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - David Margolik, "At the Bar", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty 11th Annual Conference - folder containing notes and materials gathered at conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty - Conference follow - ups, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - New Jersey Case Summaries - No Penalty Trial, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - New Jersey Case Summaries - Penalty Trial/Death, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - New Jersey Case Summaries - Penalty Trial/Life, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Notes on costs of capital punishment, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Woodrow Wilson School Policy Conference - Leigh Bienen and Douglas Mills: A Decade of Capital Punishment in New Jersey: A Report to the State Legislative, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - WWS Policy Conference on Capital Punishment, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Appendixes from New Jersey Death Penalty Study, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Leigh Bienen, Douglas Mills, et. al., A Decade of Capital Punishment in New Jersey - Presented to the New Jersey Assembly Judiciary Committee, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Leigh B. Bienen and Douglas L. Mills, "Race and County Disparities in Capital Case Processing in New Jersey.", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Capital Jury Project - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Capital Jury Project - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Capital Jury Project - Working Paper 7, "In Their Own Words: How Capital jurors Explain their Life or Death Sentencing Decisions", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Chicago Prosecutor Misconduct, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Criteria for Exemption from Human Subjects Review by the Institutional Review Panel (IRP), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia Law and Society Paper - Notes and tables to publish, 1992 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Herbert I. Weisberg and Xiu Chen, "Can Statistics Reveal when A Death Sentence is Disproportionate?" (Draft), 1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Leigh Bienen, "A Good Murder", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Leigh Bienen, "A Good Murder", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Capital Jury Project - Bringing in New Jersey, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Capital Jury Project - denial of permission to interview jurors, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Capital Jury Project - Interview's Guide, ca. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Capital Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument, ca. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Connecticut v. Michael Ross, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Flyer - The Jury Project, ca. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Trials Sorted by County/Sentence Date, ca. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - The New Jersey Jury Project: National Study of Juror Decision Making in Capital Cases - Juror Interview Instrument, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Testimony of Leigh B. Bienen Before the Joint Subcommittee of the Supreme Court Committee on Criminal Practice and Rules of Evidence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Untitled Manuscript draft with notes and annotations [may be early draft of Leigh Bienen, "The Proportionality Review of Capital Cases by State High Courts After Gregg: Only The Appearance of Justice", ca. 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Book Review Manuscript, ca. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Book Review - Manuscript and Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conference Materials - Homicide Research Working Group Workshop, 1994; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Jury Survey, Matt, 1994 Fall (Floppy-disk 1)
  - The New Jersey Jury Project - Juror Interview Instrument, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - United States v. Salvatore Lombardino - Government's Memorandum in Support of it's motion for an Anonymous Jury, 1999 September 15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "A Compilation and Comparison of Statistics concerning Application of the 1977 Illinois Death Penalty", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - James R. Acker and Charles S. Lanier, "Statutory Measures for More Effective Appellate Review of Capital Cases" with notes, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - David Baldus, James R. Acker, Leigh Bienen, et. al., Comments on Proposed Uniform Rules for Capital Case Reports and Proposed Capital Case Data Report form, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Elected Judiciary - Encyclopedia of the American Constitution, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Former CA Justice discussing influence of retention vote on Justice, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gallup Poll - death penalty opinion, 1995; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Governor Assails U.S. Delays of Death Cases," Comment re: political pressure on Judges to sentence to death, cite for only 5909 all federal habeas, 1995; 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Material from Jim Acker on Legislative History of New York Death Penalty, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Douglas Mills, David Weisburd, New Jersey v. Joseph Harris, Logical Regression, and New Jersey v. Donald Loftin, with notes, 1995; 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notes and Annotation on uniform Rules For Capital Case Data Reports, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Prospective Appointments, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Research Table of State death Penalty decision and legislation dates, ca. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Syllabus - "Persuasion: The Art of Writing In, For, and about the Law", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - A. Leigh Hicks, "The Constitutional of Imposing the Death Sentence on a Non-slayer Participant", ca. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Appendix A: Preparing a Factual Basis for the Systematic Examination of Racial and Geographical Disparities: The Court's Responsibility, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Death Row Statistics, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Intimate Partner Homicide in Chicago over 29 Years, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mental Health Preference Declaration, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Douglas Mills and New Jersey v. Joseph Harris, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Douglas Mills and New Jersey v. Donald Loftin, 1996; 1997 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Pennsylvania Supreme Court Reversals in Capital Cases, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Capital Jury Project - William J. Bowers and Benjamin D. Steinen, "Death by False Choice and Forced Choice: Empirical Evidence of Misguided Discretion in Capital Sentencing", (Draft), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Philosophy and Public Affairs copy center request form, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - List of Illinois Supreme Court opinions in Death Penalty Cases, 1979-1997, ca. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Leigh B. Bienen, "The Quality of Justice in Capital Cases: Illinois as a Case Study", 1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Leigh B. Bienen, "The Quality of Justice in Capital Cases: Illinois as a Case Study", 1998 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "Federal Death Penalty Cases: Recommendations Concerning the Cost and Quality of Defense Representation", 1998 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Illinois State Archives, Chicago Historical Society, and notes of other historical records repository on Chicago Tribune article, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Horace Kelly case on competency to be executed, ca. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Pennsylvania v. Mumia Abu - Jamal, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Prosecuting Judges, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Public Confidence in Criminal Justice System, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Questions for Homicide Class, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - State Death Penalty Cases Filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit, 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Teaching Criminal Law & Procedure: the Mentally Disabled Defendant, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Chicago Prosecutor Misconduct, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Findings and Recommendations of the Special Supreme Court Committee on Capital Cases (Illinois), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Illinois v. Anthony Porter, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Publication Correspondence - "The Quality of Justice in Capital Cases: The Illinois Experience", 1999 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - George W. Bush and Death Penalty, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Illinois Appellate Court Judge Morton Zwick political donations, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Illinois Budget Appropriations Legislation for State Defense and Prosecution, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Illinois Capital Crime Litigation Act legislation with annotations, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "Leigh's Law: Searching for Patterns in Chicago Crime", 2000 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Renata Strok, et. al., "Neuropsychological Characteristics of Death Row Inmates", 2000 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Capital punishment data, Fiscal Impact Report of Illinois House Bill and two Articles on costs of Death Penalty, 2001; 2006; 2009 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Illinois Supreme Court Capital Punishment Rules, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Lethal Injection - Physician Participation, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - David Smith v. Illinois - On Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the Supreme Court of Illinois, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "Nothing Short of Justice", 2002 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Glenn L. Pierce and Michael L. Radelet, "Race, Region, and Death Sentencing in Illinois, 1988-1997", 2002 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Report of the Governor's Commission on Capital Punishment [1 of 4], 2002 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Report of the Governor's Commission on Capital Punishment [2 of 4], 2002 (Box 3, Folder 60)